Saraba chikyuu yo, tabidatsu fune wa
Farewell Earth, a ship is taking off
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
A New Voyage
Space Battleship
Ucyuu no kanata Iskandar he unmei seoi ima tobitatsu
It's about to take off to Iscandar carrying the fate of humanity
Kanarazu koko he kaette kuru to
We'll return for sure
Te wo furu hito ni egao de kotae
Smile back at the people waving their hands
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Are you certain ?
I double-checked with Ginga's systems.
Iscandar executed a warp.
We don't think it was a natural phenomenon.
Iscandar left orbit, and accelerated
toward the Milky Way Galaxy.
Someone can move a planet at will ?
Assuming that Iscandar
warps out on the same line...
...the closest fleet we have is...
Yamato...
This is Melda Dietz,
the Royal Attendant of Iscandar.
Identify your affiliation.
I repeat, identify your affiliation.
Iscandar's been materialized in the current space-time.
No loss of mass.
No abnormality in atmospheric composition.
I still hear the noise, Daeder.
Looks like we brought it along with Iscandar.
Our home, Dezariam, is still too far away.
In order to transport a whole planet, we have to repeat a jump in the current space-time.
For the millennial dream of Dezariam...
...Iscandar is all we need.
We don't need the noise.
A dying planet...
Where has it been transported to ?
Watch out !
So annoying.
They've come.
Finally caught up, huh ?
All ships, begin anti-aerial combat !
Drive them out !
Act as a shield for the migration convoy.
Don't let even one ship get through.
The enemy fleet has begun to move.
At this rate, the Berger Fleet
will face a bilateral attack.
How about eliminating the enemy's
main force with the Desler Cannon ?
No. That would damage the
migration convoy in the sea.
Emergency message from the
Royal Attendant of Iscandar.
Your Excellency... Your Excellency Desler...
Melda Dietz ?! Where are you ?
I'm engaged in combat.
Your Excellency, please contact Lady Starsha.
She's refusing to evacuate. Please hurry.
There's a way of saving them.
If we let them undergo the ritual so they can be
accepted at Sanktel, as Melda has suggested...
Do you know what it would mean to
put a human life through that ritual ?
Yurisha, you are too young
to grasp what it means.
But at this rate, everything will be lost !
Sister, that's not for you to decide !
Sasha has been kept like that because...
So, the subspace gate can take us
to the drifting Iscandar right away ?
Then why don't we just go ?
We’re the closest, right?
We owe Iscandar for coming to Earth’s aid, don’t we?
And this is why you're
seen as such a simpleton !
The issue is, who blew up Planet Garmillas.
If it was the Bolar Federation...
...our technology exchange
with Garmillas will be canceled.
We've come this far to assemble this.
Why ?
Earth and Garmillas have a security treaty.
That could be broken, right ?
If we try to save Iscandar, Earth might be
caught in a war between Garmillas and Bolar.
It's time to give up ?
Earth has been hit by disasters, so we can't
afford to get involved in others' battles.
I've heard the Garmillas refugees
have landed on Iscandar.
Can we at least rescue them ?
Our enemy can move an inhabited planet.
Combat will be unavoidable.
Command HQ won't approve.
We just pretend not to see ?
Father, how would you talk to big bro Yabu ?
He used to visit us, right ?
He's a clumsy but kind person.
This is just too cruel for him.
I want to know your thoughts, Captain.
The subspace gate is right ahead...
...and the situation is time-sensitive.
Everyone's on edge, and this
voyage could be canceled.
What should we do ?
Don’t do this, big bro Yabu !
Let me go.
No. You can't take a landing
boat without permission !
What's with you guys ?
I've gotta go !
Hey, please calm down.
You can't be serious.
It's suicidal to go through the
subspace gate in a landing boat.
Not exactly.
This is a prototype core you've
been building on the Asuka, isn't it ?
Yabu, you're stealing a prototype.
It can help get you through
the gate. But then what ?
Even if you're lucky enough to reach Iscandar...
I don't care !
There's no place for me here.
No, I never had one.
That's why I went to Garmillas.
I finally found my place and...
...my family !
Why was a useless dork like myself even born ?!
What purpose do I even live for ?!
My family gave me all the answers !
It's where I belong !
I can't lose them.
I won't allow that to happen.
They must be alive.
I've got to save them.
You're right. They must be alive.
When your family is found, you have
to be there for them, right Yabu ?
Please calm down and...
Stop it.
Reality is cruel.
The worst always happens.
Ryusuke !
Honest but clumsy people
always become the target...
...especially those fools who keep
everything to themselves until they die.
Let him do whatever he wants.
We all become desperate...
Don't talk like you know !
What's wrong with you ?
Why did you sneak onto the Yamato then ?
Hey, Tasuke !
You wanted to test Captain Kodai, didn't you ?
You wanted him to prove he'd be worthy of your father's death and the future of Earth !
No one can do that !
If you had given up hope in people,
you wouldn't have tested the Captain !
You have hope, right ?!
You haven't given up, have you ?!
It's the same for us !
Enough.
I've seen enough.
I'll leave the Yamato.
Domon...
Coming here was a mistake.
Just put me in a cell.
That'll save you work, right Hoshina ?
Captain Kodai, that's impossible.
If we reach Iscandar,
we won't be able to avoid combat.
That'll endanger the future of Earth.
Ambassador Barrel understands that...
...even though he doesn't
know his family's situation.
Thank you for what
you've done for Yabu.
I didn't see anything.
Although the Captain is in a meeting,
you have to tell him about your resignation.
I know.
Do you ?
You think you know...
But you haven't seen anything,
or heard anything yet, for that matter.
70% of Earth's population was
lost because of Garmillas attacks.
And 70% of the Garmillas people were lost
due to the destruction of their home planet.
What should we chalk this
coincidence up to? "Karma” ?
No, that’s not a word I’d use.
To me, this seems to
be some kind of sign.
Both Earth and Garmillas are equally scarred.
We have to leave the past behind and
help each other in the truest sense.
The time is now,
when everyone's feeling anxious.
We shouldn't make decisions
according to our own convenience.
There are many humanoid
life forms in this universe.
They're not for conflict,
but for inspiration and improvement.
At least, humans believe so and act...
Captain Kodai...
Is that an insight you gained
in the higher dimension ?
No, I don't remember anything from then.
I see.
In the higher dimension, they say
all time lines exist in parallel.
If you remembered anything,
you could see the future.
In this world, everything is undetermined.
Even if you think you're right,
we can't take any risks...
...especially when the Earth ambassador with
plenary powers, the Garmillas ambassador, and...
...the fleet commander, who operates the
entire Earth force, are on board the Yamato.
No matter what.
So stupid.
Huh ?
Everyone's so stupid.
Don't you have to return
to the Asuka, Caroline ?
Why bother ?
The training will probably be canceled.
Next time you call me
by that name, I'll kill you.
Oh, Tokugawa, you're the healer.
Got it.
Guys...
I need your help.
The fleet will reach the subspace gate soon.
The original plan was to jump all
the way to the Magellanic Cloud, but...
Defense Fleet 65 has been recalled.
We can't enter the gate. I'm sorry.
I understand your feelings,
but on the Earth side...
Abnormality in the wave motion engine.
You can't stop the pressure increase ?!
The energy condenser's begun
to melt down for an unknown reason.
Tasuke's job is to tamper
with the wave motion engine.
Bando will re-write the damage control information, making the engine look like it's out of control.
Fire in the engine room.
I'm sealing the doors.
Just for 10 minutes, shut down access to the
engine room to gain control of the Yamato's thrusters.
Once the ship enters the gate,
we have no choice but to go forward.
What's going on ?
Once we get to Iscandar, we win.
The Yamato can take necessary actions within the
scope of self-defense and humanitarian assistance.
That must be the crew's wish. So...
What's happening ?
An evacuation order has been
issued by the engine section.
Please move to the Hyuga.
Wha...
We'll escort the three big shots out.
This is not the intent of the Earth government.
The Yamato is heading to Iscandar because of a revolt by its new recruits, and we have to show it to the world.
This won't just end with only a discharge.
You can say no, but even
if it's just me, I have to...
Game's over.
Your act of revolt and control of the ship's
operations is a serious offense.
Why didn’t you confide in
me before taking action ?
Don't you know I've done this before ?
Sir.
Hey, you there !
What's the meaning of this ?!
Attention. This is Kodai,
Captain of the Yamato speaking.
Defense Fleet 65 will head to the Magellanic Cloud.
This is not by the order of Earth
Command HQ, but of our own volition.
If you don't agree with this,
let me know, and...
...I'll ask the Garmillas patrol on the Magellan side of the gate to accommodate you.
We're entering a battlefield.
We'll be in tough situations.
But the Yamato is not just a battleship.
She's the hope of mankind.
We never lose hope, no matter what.
She's the embodiment of human will.
Whatever happens, never give up.
Keep trying.
Seek peace in a hateful conflict.
Based on human ideals, we'll try to
save as many people as possible.
I hope all of you will do your very best.
Oh man, we were forced out
of the bunch, weren't we ?
The higher in rank you go,
the more boring the job becomes.
On the other hand, the young
ones can do the jobs they want.
We'll have to talk to the
government to ensure their status.
Okita's children and their children
are taking a step forward.
Geshtam wall output down.
Launch mines.
Defend the migration convoy.
The damage is spreading out.
Don't let them come any closer.
We can't lose any more Gamilan lives.
Führer...
Don't worry.
I felt dizzy. That's all.
But...
Transmission from the Crystal Palace.
Abelt...
Starsha...
What are you doing ?
Get out of there at once.
Even if you have to desert Iscandar...
I can't leave.
We're Iscandar’s guardians.
We are unable to leave this planet.
Just as your kind can't live separated
from Garmillas for too long, neither can we...
Such a waste of resources and effort...
Iscandar is all we want.
We eliminated Planet Garmillas
because it hindered our purpose.
Why do you keep resisting ?
Who are you ?
We are Dezariam.
To those weak beings
who don't leave any mark in history...
Begone !
What was that ?
No way...
That's...
So, you've come, Yamato...
Save Iscandar! Rebellion of the Young Heroes!!
Episode 4
Emergency Order! Yamato, Shoot Iscandar !!
Next Time
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Shiro Sanada:
Ryusuke Domon:
Miyako Kyozuka:
Heiji Bando:
Shigeru Sakamoto:
Caroline Raiden:
Tasuke Tokugawa:
Tetsuya Kitano:
Toru Hoshina:
Kotetsu Serizawa:
Osamu Yamanami:
Heikuro Todo:
Saki Todo:
Susumu Yamazaki:
Tetsuya Kitano:
Haruo Nishina:
Analyzers:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Hochu Otsuka
Tasuku Hatanaka
Tomo Muranaka
Wataru Hatano
Kento Ito
Chitose Morinaga
Nobuhiko Okamoto
Ryuichi Kijima
Motoki Takagi
Tessho Genda
Masashi Ebara
Toshihiko Kojima
Ayahi Takagaki
Hiroshi Tsuchida
Ryuichi Kijima
Kenta Miyake
Cho
Abelt Desler:
Gadel Talan:
Wolf Flaken:
Melda Dietz:
Fomt Berger:
Loren Barrel:
Yarb Skerge:
Vance Baren:
Hilde Shultz:
Koichi Yamadera
Kotaro Yakamura
Akimitsu Takase
Shizuka Ito
Junichi Suwabe
Masaki Terasoma
Cho
Shinya Fukumatsu
Ayano Miura
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Starsha:
Yurisha:
Mœlders:
Daeder:
Dezariam Soldier A:
Dezariam Soldier B:
Garmillas Soldier:
Yamato Crewman A:
Yamato Crewman B:
Kikuko Inoue
Houko Kuwashima
Takaya Kuroda
Masuo Amada
Keisuke Hamaoka
Takahiro Ayase
Yujiro Kakuda
Hiroki Maeda
Ryuichi Hirose
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru